Philippe VINCON 11 impasse des jardinets 94 520 Périgny sur Yerres

France

French Cell: + 00 33 6 47 82 96 02 Email: vincon.philippe@wanadoo.fr

Driving license: Yes



#### **EXECUTIVE MANAGEMENT**

A proven leader with demonstrated strategic insight and operational drive. Builds teams that produce revenue and profit results; expertise in general management, domestic and international sales and marketing. Able to strike balance between long-term nature of the industry and near-term financial requirements and continuously enhance value of the business. Seasoned ability to anticipate and manage change in a rapidly evolving, fragmented and highly competitive industry. Skillful and creative critical analysis. Combines high-energy level with initiative and a tireless work ethic. My management is based on the following concepts: SMART (Specific Measurable Achievable Realistic Time-Bound)

AIDA: (Awareness Interest Desire Action Management)

#### **MAIN SKILLS**

- Merger & Acquisition Audit Strategic Economic Intelligence
- Analysis of market opportunities & segments (Nielsen-Iri-Xerfi-Business Insight-Data monitor-Eurostat-Kantarpanel-Gira)
- Development and implementation of Formal strategic plans (Geopolitical context-Law BusinessDevelopment-Lobbying-Leadership Management to develop share of markets)
- Business Sales development (product offering, pricing, merchandising, marketing, sales, Brand Management-Digital Net Work)
- A proven track record in negotiations in Network (On Trade Off Trade On line)
- Control and management KPI business Financial Analysis Risk Management-Process Incoterms
- To manage a defined group of products to satisfy the needs of Customer, achieving sales, stock and profit targets
- Managing technical and industrial projects, Managing Spply Chain Process «OEA» label
- Practice Production Scheduling Supply Chain Management HACCP Project Management Certification BRC ISO IFS-R&D development with Eurofins Company-Reflexion participation R&D
- Knowledge: Network of leader company Management by the leadership «Skills-Encouraging entrepreneurial method- Listening to the Consumers and the Costumers»

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Export General Manager - PARIS - FRANCE 2015 -2016 http://www.martineteuropa.com

USA - Middle East - Chicago - New Jersey New York - Washington DC

MARKET / CHILLED BEVERAGES Healthy Foods - Veggies -

Contacts Brokers & Distributors

http://www.dpispecialtyfoods.com : http://www.kehe.com. https://www.unfi.com

Leaders on these Markets: <a href="http://www.bolthouse.com">http://www.odwalla.com</a>. <a href="http://www.odwalla.com">http://www.odwalla.com</a>.

EMIRATS: DUBAI - ABOU DABI - UK: LONDON - CANADA: MONTREAL- DOM TOM

Contacts Brokers & Distributors /Business France / Gulfood/

## TRANSITION MANAGER- PARIS - FRANCE 2011-2014 http://www.akera.fr

## SAS AKERA – REAL ESTATE

Mains missions:

Responsible for 30 Million € in revenue

Managed a team of 10 people

Main missions:

To sell stocks (Apartments Network CGP, Market Place, Set-up Web Site)

To manage P&L (Margin-Sales)

#### **CONSULTANT - PARIS - FRANCE 2009 - 2011**

Completed missions providing strategic advice to business leaders. Analyzed current situation and developed forward looking business opportunities including KPI's related to organizational needs, product offerings and sales potential in support of the decision making process.

#### Main missions:

- The World Halieutic Market: Analysis & development of products
- Project T-BAR Retail (Corner-Travel-Mall market): India towards Europe
- World Screening: Economic Intelligence (Studies pesticides 2018-Politique Agricole Commune-Projet Blogosphère IE)
- Strategic Audits (Cookies Trade, Cooked Dishes, Cheeses-Wines and Spirits): Research for development of export
- Analysis and sourcing in the food-processing industry, the white protein and poultry sector in particular at the world level
- Bioyou: Development, preparation of a business plan for a new branded organic drink, raising funds, deposited at the INPI Development R&D with the leaders of the aromas market
- In association with The CBRE group: Research for specialized retail places in the USA-Asia-London & Sweden
- With the American logistician C.H. Robinson studied the possible partnership with a fast food chain for a logistic deployment in Asia
- Analysis of potential E-Procurement solutions in the fast food industry
- Project development in Retail Dubai EAU with AL MAKTOUM FUNDS, MELLERIO dits Meller
- Studies ERP Market for Industrial and Retail Companies to manage the workflow
- Research Apps Mashable to develop the brands on new Tech-Savy

# INTERIM CEO: WAGRAM-RESIDENCES – MAISONS PIERRE-Paris-France <u>www.maisons-pierre.com</u>2006 – 2008

#### Main missions:

- Responsible transition management of division Real Estate
- Reporting Shareholders-Bank
- Developed relationships with the local elected representatives
- Responsible for 10 Million € in revenue in France (B2C sales)
- Managed a team of 10 people
- Responsible for coordinating sales and promotion of 15 to 20 housing projects
- Responsible for sales agreements , manage costs of construction sites, working with solicitor and notary
- Responsible for balance sheets assessments, overall financials in line with selected KPI's in the income statement

#### ADENTS - Paris - France www.adents.com 2004 - 2008

# - CO - FOUNDER and Shareholders : Start-up ADENTS

- Main missions: Industry: NTIC, traceability system, specializes in unit identification
- Development and implementation of the business plan
- Recruited 3 engineers technical (Visual basic,C++)
- Contact with investment funds (Siparex, Bank of Vizille, Equitis, Provestis)
- Raising funds (Natixis CapHornInvest): 3 Million €
- Development share of B2B market, pharmaceutical products, food-processing industry, wines&spirits
- Network to develop «Canada-USA»

# VRANKEN POMMERY MONOPOLE – REIMS- FRANCE <a href="http://www.vrankenpommery.com/fr/pre-home-1">http://www.vrankenpommery.com/fr/pre-home-1</a> 1999 - 2003

#### **DIRECTOR OF DEVELOPMENT**

Main missions:

### Director for Commercial Development:

- Industry: Champagnes, Wines and Spirits
- Responsible for 120 Million € in revenue
- Improved gross sales by + 40 %
- Managed a team of 50 people
- Head of industrial sales negotiation at customer purchase centers
- Led international negotiations with varying laws by country
- Process orders for Digital Data Exchange Services (Publipromo Internet)
- Developed marketing and merchandising plans with Leclerc-Carrefour, Auchan, Casino, Delhaize, France Boissons, CWT
- Installation and dashboard piloting of NSI (Net Sale Income)
- Led the commercial negotiations of sales and the re-construction of the operational margins
- Negotiation with importers (USA UK HONG-KONG-JAPAN)

## Director for Supply Chain Development:

- 3 production sites and 1 logistic site
- Managed a team of 150 people
- Restructured information and logistic flow (processing, production, logistic)
- Set up BRC IFS HACCP with Eurofins
- Rationalized processes for purchasing, supply, inventory control, handling, transport
- Implemented maintenance checks for industrial tools
- Implemented traceability measures according to EAN 128 standards
- Implemented Digital Data Exchange principles (Order -DESADV)
- Optimized the progression of Rate of Services (98%)
- Shared management of provisions and installation of a new ERP Adonix X3-
- Project managed for Log+Manugistics, Inc.
- Redefined and implemented performance indicators linked to profitability

# SYSTEME U: Purchasing National Group- Paris <a href="http://www.magasins-u.com/portailu/national/supermarche-hypermarche-u">http://www.magasins-u.com/portailu/national/supermarche-hypermarche-u</a>

CASINO: Purchasing National Group - Saint Etienne http://www.groupe-casino.fr/

# 1992 - 1999

- Main missions: Category Manager
- Market Beverage sector without Alcohol Wines and spirits
- Hypermarket -Supermarket distribution retail
- Revenue : 250/255 million €uro

- Installation and development of segment management categories
- Purchasing, merchandising and marketing product offerings (national brand-private label first price)
- Import of «concentrated» fruit juice
- Negotiation industrial purchases Monitoring of margins/P&L
- Negotiation with laboratories (Quality system Control)

Confédération Nationale des Caves Particulières-Paris,(CNPC) <a href="http://www.vigneron-independant.com/">http://www.vigneron-independant.com/</a>
1992

Market: Wines

#### Main missions:

- Responsible for the accounts of the confederation of individual wine cellars-Paris

E.LECLERC-Alsace http://www.e-leclerc.com/magasin/altkirchhttp://www.e-leclerc.com/magasin/hirsingue

1991

Market

- General Manager Wines and spirits in two E.LECLERC store

# BONGRAIN "C'est si bon Fine French Foods "Chicago - New York" U.S.A 1989

Market Retail: Luxury Food &Wines and Spirits

**Development Project Manager** 

# Main missions:

- Market Retail Catering Restaurant
- Set-up shops
- Business Sales Manager development retail catering animation
- Importation of wines and spirits and all clearing administration to import on the US Market
- (Agreement of label, BATF Distributing importer)
- Follow-up of the margins of exploitation ticket means -attendance company CAB to B
- Animation and development of products by network (Customers Shops-Catering B to B

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Office Suite Proficiency (PC & MAC) | Tech-Savy (iPhone & iPad Apps)

I Internet Research & Purchasing I

Office Equipment Management | Documents Management | Email Management | MS Office | Project AS 400 | Project SAP - ADONIX X3 | NIELSEN Technology | MICROS Systems, Inc. | JD EDWARDS ORACLE | CDNetworks | ITRACEABILITY SYSTEM

## **EDUCATION**

2002 EMBA/CPA/HEC

1989 Diplôme International de Commerce

1989 BTS Vins et Spiritueux

1987 Diplôme de Sommelier

1985 BT Hôtelier

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 12/24/1966

Civil Status: Married with 2 grown up children

Languages: French (native), English (business fluency), German (7 years of studies at school)